DHANYA PASUPLAN

HR Generalist | Employee Relations | Talent Acquisition

@ dpasupalan@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/dhanya-pasupalan-25077b134

Mavelikkara , Kerala Ph: +91-9961261794

SUMMARY

Enthusiastic HR Generalist with 3+ years of experience in HR roles. Proven skills in employee relations, talent acquisition and career guidance. Articulate negotiator skillful in supporting competitive company growth by sourcing top-quality applicants for critical roles. Organized planner with excellent team leadership and program management abilities

EXPERIENCE

Career Advisor

B-GHUD Academy

🗰 01/2024 - Present

Mavelikkara, Kerala

- Provided personalized career guidance and counseling to students, primarily nurses, aspiring to work in the UK, New Zealand, Ireland, and other Englishspeaking countries.
- Assisted students in understanding the certification requirements, licensure processes, and visa procedures necessary for employment in their desired destinations.
- Collaborated with recruitment agencies and healthcare institutions in the UK, New Zealand, Ireland, etc., to identify job opportunities for qualified nursing professionals.
- Facilitated the recruitment process by connecting eligible candidates with prospective employers hence improving the success rate to 40 %

Recruitment Executive

Connectors HR

m 08/2022 - 04/2023

Bengaluru, Karnataka

- Sourcing candidates from portals like Naukri, LinkedIn, etc and Screening candidates for availability, interest level, and qualifications
- Coordinating with candidates post interview selection for onboarding
- MIS Reports status of joining/requirements assigned.
- Tracked candidates and pushed for feedback on disqualifications, time-to-fill statistics and other variable

Academic Coordinator

B-GHUD Academy

= 01/2021 - 08/2021

Mavelikkara, Kerala

- Promoted program courses, activities and accomplishments, both internally and externally, to boost recruitment and retain diverse student body.
- Guided and supported faculty and staff in development of new programs
- Tracking Admissions and doing continuous follow ups to ensure client satisfaction

Business Development Executive

White Oval Technologies

- Collaborated with sales and marketing departments to support client acquisition.
- Identified and pursued valuable business opportunities to generate new company revenue and improve bottom line profit.
- Established and maintained highly effective relationships with clients and industry partners to drive growth.

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration

Girideepam Business School

= 06/2016 - 08/2018

Kottayam, Kerala

Bachelor of Technology

Sri Vellapalli Nateshan College Of Engineering

苗 2012 - 2016 👂 Mavelikkara , Kerala

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

Increased Employee Retention

Implemented employee engagement programs. resulting in a 20% increase in retention rates.



Enhanced Onboarding Process

Streamlined the onboarding process, reducing time-to-productivity by 25% and improving new hire satisfaction.



Successful Talent Acquisition

Led recruitment efforts, filling all requirements for the role and reducing time-to-fill by 30%.



Developed Career Guidance Policies

Created and implemented New policies that ensured compliance with employment laws and improved process efficiency.

SKILLS

Employee Relations

Talent Acquisition

HR Policies

Teamwork

G-Suite

Microsoft Office

PASSIONS



Employee Engagement

Passionate about creating an engaging and inclusive work environment for all employees.



Continuous Learning

Committed to ongoing professional development and staying updated on HR trends and practices.